Dupont Circle Community Association Records 106
People's Archive, MLK Library
Dupont Circle Community Association Records
1972-1978
People's Archive, MLK Library
Dupont Circle Community Association
106
1.5 Linear feet
3 Boxes
Arrangement
Series I: Organizational Materials This series contains meeting minutes, photographs, and a history of the organization. Series II: Zoning This series contains legal documents, correspondence, clippings, and a copy of the DC Zoning Regulations.
Biographical / Historical
The Dupont Circle Community Association was formed in May 1922. The goals of the organization were "the advancement of the city's housing conditions; school betterment; traffic regulations; and fair and equitable rates for public service corporations, especially street car fares and electric light rates." The North Dupont area boundaries were defined as Florida Avenue to the west, T Street to the north, and 15th Street to the south. In the 1970s, the Dupont Circle Community Association was involved in a number of legal disputes over property and zoning regulations, including a proposed plan to demolish the Salvation Army Building at 1800 Corcoran Street NW.
Custodial History
This collection was donated by Joseph A. Glover of the Dupont Circle Community Association.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of meeting minutes, legal documents, clippings, and correspondence related to the Dupont Circle Community Association.
Housing; Neighborhoods; Organizational Records; Community organization; Legal documents; Correspondence; Minutes (Records)
- Series 1: Organizational Materials
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains meeting minutes, photographs, and a history of the organization.
  - History, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes and General Paperwork, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photos of Columbine by Paul Crumrine, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photos, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series 2: Zoning
  This series contains legal documents, correspondence, clippings, and a copy of the DC Zoning Regulations.
  - Connecticut Avenue, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Connecticut Avenue, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Demolition of Housing, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Underpass, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Metro Elevator, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Salvation Army, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Salvation Army, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Legal Documents Re: Salvation Army, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Legal Documents Re: Salvation Army, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Legal Documents Re: Salvation Army, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Legal Documents Re: Salvation Army, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Legal Documents Re: Salvation Army, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Legal Documents Re: Salvation Army, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Legal Documents: Board of Zoning Adjustment, 1972, 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Court Cases: Appeals, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Regulation Amendments and Rezoning, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Zoning Adjustment, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Zoning Adjustment, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Zoning Adjustment, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Zoning Regulations, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Zoning Clippings, 1971-1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)